# BILL **HRONIS**, PMP

## Toronto ONTARIO 416.456.9794

#### bill.hronis@outlook.com

A certified project management professional with over 10 years' experience managing projects and a passion for learning. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to overcome challenges and motivate teams. Known among staff and colleagues for strong leadership, attention to detail and positive attitude no matter the complexity of the challenge.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### OCTOBER 2018 - OCTOBER 2020

**DIRECTOR - PMO, CI INVESTMENTS INC.** 

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

- ✓ Lead a team of 8 Program/Project managers within the PMO, overseeing individual and team development, motivation and performance.
- ✓ Oversaw team members in the planning, development and execution of initiatives tied to corporate strategic objectives.
- ✓ Mentored non-PMO project managers within various IT departments companywide on project management practices implemented by the PMO including the benefits of agile development.
- ✓ Collaborated with executive project sponsors in the development of project business cases, identifying expected value and benefits realization.
- ✓ Collaborated with C-suite to identify areas of improvement in project management and overall PMO process improvements.
- ✓ Delivered quarterly portfolio status updates to C-suite, including progress and risk factors related to corporate objectives.
- ✓ Reduced complexity and confusion by developing and implementing an automated end-to end project intake process providing a single point of truth of all company project initiatives.
- ✓ Elevated the standards for all project with PMO oversight by developing and implementing a PMO project governance structure.
- ✓ Developed and implemented a custom, interactive project dashboard using Microsoft Power BI, effectively communicating status updates of the full portfolio of projects to C-suite with the ability to drill down to program and project specific data.
- ✓ Developed a project portfolio review and selection process for evaluate project alignment with corporate strategy to effectively remove bias from the project prioritization and selection process.

#### **OCTOBER 2013 – OCTOBER 2018**

#### **PROGRAM MANAGER - PMO, CI INVESTMENTS INC.**

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

- ✓ Assumed responsibility of a program two years past due and over \$5 million in sunk cost leading the team to a successful rebuild and launch within six months.
- ✓ Lead the first major agile project within the organization showcasing the benefits of agile development leading to widespread adoption of agile methodologies throughout development teams' companywide.

- ✓ Successful completion of various medium to large business programs/projects tied to corporate objectives from project initiation to project close.
- ✓ Liaised various departments, including IT silos, product, marketing, legal and communications to ensure common understanding and commitment to project objectives.
- ✓ Designated MS Project team specialist, assisting team members with any challenges, roadblocks or questions related to using and operating MS Project.
- ✓ Trusted to lead projects of the most demanding project sponsors within the organization to ensure an orderly and organized project execution, meeting project objective.

#### **AUGUST 2007 – OCTOBER 2013**

#### MANAGER - PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT & GOVERNANCE, CLINVESTMENTS INC.

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

- ✓ Developed, implemented and managed segregated fund products generating billions in sales while working closely with insurance partners to ensure available products continued to meet client needs.
- ✓ Demonstrated success in the development and deployment of training materials, to ensure a comprehensive understanding of new product offerings.
- ✓ Provided creative solutions to product issues and gathered information on customer experiences for future product enhancements.

#### **SKILLS**

- Portfolio, Program & Project Management
- Leadership & Team Development
- Strategic Planning and Alignment
- Stakeholder Management
- Problem Resolution

- Microsoft Office/Teams
- JIRA/Confluence
- Project Online/Power BI
- Waterfall/Agile Methodologies
- Effective Communications
   Prioritization & Time Management

### **EDUCATION/CERTIFICATION**

**PROJECT MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION,** PROJECT MANAGEMENT INSTITUTE | 2022

**FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATE,** UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO SCHOOL OF CONTINUING STUDIES | 2021

**LEADING PROJECTS IN ORGANIZATIONS CERTIFICATE,** UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO SCHOOL OF CONTINUING STUDIES | 2014

**FOUNDATIONS OF PROJECT MANAGEMENT CERTIFICATE,** UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO SCHOOL OF CONTINUING STUDIES | 2013

**COACHING AND MOTIVATION SEMINAR, GEORGIAN COLLEGE** 

MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP DEVELOPMENT/LIFO CERTIFICATE, RYERSON UNIVERSITY

**PODIUM PRESENTATION SKILL CERTIFICATE, PODIUM CONSULTING INC.** 

MARKETING DIPLOMA, CENTENNIAL COLLEGE